Guide to the Ensemble Theatre Records, 1983-2008 MS 533
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Ensemble Theatre Records
1983-2008
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Ensemble Theatre (Houston, Tex.).
MS 533
8 Linear Feet (15 boxes)
This collection contains fifteen boxes of material related to the operation of The Ensemble Theatre in Houston, Texas, including General Records, Administration Records and Financial Records.
Biography
By the time George Hawkins (1947-1991), founded the Black Ensemble Company in 1976, he already had eleven years of professional theater experience. He was an accomplished stage director as well as a stage and film actor. Hawkins graduated from Case Western Reserve University in Ohio and Prairie View A and M College in Prairie View, Texas. He furthered his professional training at Beale Street Repertory Theater in Memphis, Tennessee and New Freedom Theater in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, which included a year of study in London, England. He was the driving force behind The Ensemble Theatre until his death July 25, 1990 in Houston. Biography excerpted from A History of the Ensemble Theatre and its productions 1976-1999, a Master's thesis by Sharon Gray, University of Houston. A copy of this thesis is located in Box 3, folder 17.
Organizational Sketch
In November of 1976, Houstonian George Hawkins founded The Black Ensemble Company, Houston's first African American professional theater, to provide a venue for Houston's talented Black actors, writers and artists to perform. When his company moved into its first home at 1010 Tuam Street in Houston, Hawkins dropped the word Black from the name, becoming simply The Ensemble. The first production performed at the new site was Surprise, Surprise...A Love Story, written and directed by Hawkins. In 1985, George Hawkins and his theater supporters rented a building at 3535 Main Street, Houston, and converted it into a theater. After Hawkin's death in 1991, Eileen Morris became the artistic director and devoted her life to keeping Hawkin's dream alive. In 1993, the group, now known as The Ensemble Theatre, began a fundraising campaign to purchase the building theyhad occupied for eight years at 3535 Main Street and renovate it. This venue became the largest African American theater in the United States and was the site of many "firsts" in the history of African American professional theater. In 2004, the Ensemble Theatre reached two milestones; becoming a designated stop on the new Houston Metrorail system, and the fulfillment of the mortgage on the building, celebrated by a Mortagage Burning Ceremony on January 1, 2004.
Scope and Contents
The Ensemble Theatre Records incorporate the history of the general operation of the theater, including fundraising, advertising, and administrative Board records.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Future additions may be expected for this material.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Mrs. Audrey H. Lawson March 1, 2008.
Index Terms
Subjects
Theater; African Americans
Document Types
videotapes; posters; pamphlets; corrrespondence; clippings (information artifacts); audiotapes
Subjects (Corporations)
Ensemble Theatre (Houston, Tex.).
- Series I: Ensemble Theatre General Records, 1987-2008; 238913
  - Advertising, flyers and programs, 1987-2008.; 239065 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anadarko Petroleum, 1993-1994.; 239064 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arthur Andersen, 1993-1994.; 239063 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andersen Consulting, 1994.; 239062 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anheuser Busch, 1993-1995.; 239061 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Apache Corporation, 1994.; 239060 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Area Task Force, (Houston, Harris County), 1994.; 239059 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Audelco, (Audience Development Committee, Inc), 1994-1995.; 239058 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Auto dealerships, 1993.; 239057 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baker and Botts, LLP, 1993.; 239056 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bank of America, 1994.; 239055 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bank of Houston, 1994.; 239054 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bank One, 1993,1994.; 239053 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Black History Month, foundation and corporate support Luncheon, 1995.; 239052 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Black Theater Directory, 1993,1994.; 239051 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Blaffer Foundation, 1993, 1994.; 239050 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brentwood Baptist Church, 1995.; 239049 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brown and Root, Inc., 1993, 1994.; 239048 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brown Foundation, 1992-1997.; 239047 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Browning-Ferris Industries, 1993,1994.; 239046 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Building contracts, 1994,1995.; 239045 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Burlington Resources, 1994,1995.; 239044 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Businesses supporting the arts in Houston, 1993.; 239043 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cultural Arts Council of Houston (CACH), 1990-1996.; 239042 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Arts Council of Houston (CACH) Stabilization Enterprise, 1996-1997.; 239041 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - CAIN Foundation, 1991-1994.; 239040 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cameron Foundation, 1993-1997; 239039 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Charles R. Drew Medical Center, 1997.; 239038 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - City of Houston, 1993-1995.; 239037 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - City of Houston permits, 1992.; 239036 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clift Foundation, 1993-1994.; 239035 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Coastal Corporation, 1993.; 239034 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Coca-Cola Foods, 1993,1994.; 239033 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cockrell Foundation, 1991.; 239032 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cogen Technologies, 1995.; 239031 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Combined Federal Campaign, 1995-1996.; 239030 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Compaq Computer Foundation, 1991-1995.; 239029 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Compass Bank, 1994-1996.; 239028 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conoco, 1994-1997.; 239027 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Continental Airlines, 1997.; 239026 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cooper Industries, 1993-1996.; 239025 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Corporate contracts, 1993.; 239024 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cullen Foundation, 1990-1997.; 239023 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cullen Trust for Performing Arts, 1994, 1995.; 239022 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ossie Davis and Ruby Dee performance contracts (includes audio cassette), 1992.; 239021 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Delloite and Touche, 1994.; 239020 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Demotte Energy Corporation, 1994.; 239019 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Destec Energy, 1993,1994.; 239018 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Don Coleman and Associates, 1995.; 239017 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Douglas M. Lawson Associates, Inc., 1993.; 239016 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Duncan Foundation, 1991-1993.; 239015 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Eli Lilly and Company Foundation, 1996.; 239014 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Elkins Foundation, 1993.; 239013 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Eller Media Company, 1995.; 239012 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ellwood Foundation, 1991.; 239011 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Enos Cabell Buick-Mazda, 1995.; 239010 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Enron Foundation, 1991-1997.; 239009 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Entex, 1994.; 239008 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Entrix, 1994.; 239007 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - EXXON Corporation USA, 1991-1995.; 239006 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Exxon Education Foundation, 1993-1995.; 239005 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Farish Foundation, 1991-1997.; 239004 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Favrot Fund, 1993.; 239003 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Fiesta Mart, 1993-1994.; 239002 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Finger Furniture Foundation, 1993.; 239001 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - First Interstate Bank, 1994.; 239000 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fish Foundation, 1991-1994.; 238999 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Fluor Daniel, 1993-1995.; 238998 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Flyers, 1987-2008.; 238997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Foleys, 1993-1998.; 238996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fondren Foundation, 1990-1999.; 238995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Foundation Prospects, 1991-1994.; 238994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Franklin Beauty School, 1995.; 238993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fulbright and Jaworski, 1997.; 238992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gallery Furniture, 1993, 1994.; 238991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - George Hawkins Playwright Contest, 1993-1995.; 238990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gregory Fund, 1992-1993.; 238989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gross Investments, 1995.; 238988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Guaranty Federal Bank, 1993-1995.; 238987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hamman Foundation, 1992-1994.; 238986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hankamer Foundation, 1991.; 238985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Harlem After Hours, VHS tape, Maxell GX Silver, T-120 246 Minute tape., undated.; 238984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hershey Foundation, 1992-1994.; 238983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Herzstein Charitable Foundation, 1991-1994.; 238982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Master's thesis, "A History of The Ensemble Theater and Its Productions, 1976-1999."; 238981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hobby Foundation, 1991-1995.; 238980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Honeywell, Inc, 1993-1994.; 238979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Houston Arts Fund, 1996.; 238978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Houston Businesses, 1993.; 238977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Houston Chronicle, 1993-1996.; 238976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Houston Endowment, 1996-1998.; 238975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Houston Lighting and Power, 1993-1997.; 238974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Howell Corporation, 1994.; 238973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - IBM, 1993.; 238972 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Inner Circle Memberships, 1994, 1995.; 238971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1991-1994.; 238970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - J.C. Penney Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - J.M. West Texas Corporation, 1993-1994.; 238968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Kayser Foundation, 1992- 1994.; 238967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kemper Securities, 1994.; 238966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Kentucky Fried Chicken, 1995.; 238965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kilroy Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - K-Mart, 1994.; 238963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Knox Charitable Foundation, 1992-1997.; 238962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kresge Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238961 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Kroger Food Stores, 1993-1994.; 238960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lewis Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lowe Foundation., 1991-1994.; 238958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mabee Foundation, 1993-1996.; 238957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Marathon Group, 1993-1994.; 238956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - I.W. Marks, 1993-1994."; 238955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - McGovern Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238954 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - M.D. Anderson Foundation, 1992-1997.; 238953 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Meadows Foundation, Inc., 1993-1998.; 238952 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Menil Foundation, 1993.; 238951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Merrill Lynch, 1994-1995.; 238950 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - National Endowment For the Arts, 1994-1996.; 238949 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper articles, 2006-2008.; 238948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Owsley Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Panhandle Eastern, 1994-1997.; 238946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pembroke Fund, 1992-1993.; 238945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pennzoil Company, 1993- 1995.; 238944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Percy Holt and Company Insurance, 1994-1995.; 238943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Philip Morris, 1995-1996.; 238942 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Playbills, 1981-2008.; 238941 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Powell Foundation, 1993, 1997.; 238940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Prudential, 1993-1995.; 238939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Randall's Food Markets, Inc., 1993-1995.; 238938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rauscher, Pierce, Refsnes, Inc., 1994.; 238937 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - SAH Properties, 1995.; 238936 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Schissler Charitable Foundation., 1993-1994.; 238935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Scurlock Foundation, 1993-1995.; 238934 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Shell Oil Company Foundation, 1992-1997.; 238933 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Silberstein, Maxine and Herman, 1994.; 238932 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Southwest Airlines, 1994.; 238931 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Southwestern Bell, 1994-1997.; 238930 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sterling McCall Lexus, 1995.; 238929 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Stewart Title Company, 1993.; 238928 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Swalm Foundation, 1990-1994.; 238927 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Tenneco Gas, 1993-1996.; 238926 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Texaco USA, 1989, 1991, 1994.; 238925 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Texas Casualty Insurance, 1994.; 238924 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Texas Commerce Bank Foundation, Inc, 1994-1997.; 238923 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Transamerica, 1994.; 238922 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Transco Energy Company, 1993-1995.; 238921 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Turner Charitable Foundation, 1993, 1994.; 238920 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Union Texas Petroleum, 1994.; 238919 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Unity National Bank, 1992-1997.; 238918 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Vinson and Elkins, 1993-1995, 1997.; 238917 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Weiser, Harold, 1995.; 238916 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - West Foundation, 1993-1994.; 238915 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Wheeler Avenue Baptist Church, 1995-1996.; 238914 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Series II: Ensemble Theatre Administration Records, 1983-1998, 238838
  - Ensemble Theatre calendars, 1993, 1994.; 238912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ensemble Theatre blank stationery, undated.; 238911 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1991/1992 to 1994/1995.; 238910 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board correspondence, 1990-1997.; 238909 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ensemble Theatre Board committees, 1987- 1991.; 238908 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting notes, 1992-1994.; 238907 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting documents, 1 of 2, 1997-1999.; 238906 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Board meeting documents, 2 of 2, 1997-1999.; 238905 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Ensemble Theatre Board photos, undated.; 238904 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Eric Calloway, interim director, 1996-1997.; 238903 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble Theatre capital campaign agenda, 1993.; 238902 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Capital campaign, 1993.; 238901 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Contribution request: rejections, 1993,1994.; 238900 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ensemble Theatre correspondence, 1993.; 238899 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Ensemble Theatre correspondence: in, 1989-1995.; 238898 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ensemble Theatre correspondence: out, 1989-1997.; 238897 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ensemble Theatre emblems, undated.; 238896 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ensemble Theatre faxes, 1993-1994.; 238895 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Ensemble, Ensemble Theatre floor plans, undated.; 238894 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ensemble Theatre general information, undated.; 238893 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ensemble Theatre capital campaign, 1 of 2, 1995.; 238892 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Ensemble Theatre capital campaign, 2 of 2, 1995.; 238891 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Ensemble Guild By-Laws, undated.; 238890 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Ensemble Theatre history, undated.; 238889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble theatre insurance policies, 1990-1993.; 238888 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Black Ensemble IRS correspondence, 1983.; 238887 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Audrey Lawson promotional biography, undated.; 238886 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - El Franco Lee correspondence, 1993.; 238885 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Llong-range planning correspondence:, undated.; 238884 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ensemble Theatre marketing, 1995-1996.; 238883 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ensemble Theatre memorandum, 1994.; 238882 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Barry Moore, Architect correspondence, 1994,1995.; 238881 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Irl Mowery correspondence, 1993-1997.; 238880 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Narrative Statement, undated.; 238879 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper articles, 1990-1998.; 238878 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - News release forms, samples, undated.; 238877 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - News releases, undated.; 238876 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - News releases, June 22, 1993.; 238875 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - News release, Jun 24, 1993.; 238874 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - News release, Aug 2, 1993.; 238873 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - News release, April 1, 1994.; 238872 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - News release, July 25, 1994.; 238871 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - News release, Aug 29, 1994.; 238870 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - News release, Jul 26, 1995.; 238869 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Personnel, undated.; 238868 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Personnel Committee, 1992-1995.; 238867 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ensemble Theatre personnel policy, undated.; 238866 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Planning and development audit, study report, 1993.; 238865 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Power breakfast papers, 1993.; 238864 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Press release, undated.; 238863 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Proposal enclosures, 1977-1995.; 238862 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Proposal enclosures for the City of Houston, 1992-1994.; 238861 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Publicity, 1993-1996.; 238860 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Reviews, undated.; 238859 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rotary clubs, undated.; 238858 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Armand Shapiro (President of Garden Ridge Pottery), undated.; 238857 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Signatures, undated.; 238856 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Singles programs, undated.; 238855 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - South Main Baptist Church, 1995.; 238854 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Space needs, 1995.; 238853 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Staff biographies, undated.; 238852 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Staff correspondence, 1995.; 238851 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Study questionnaire, undated.; 238850 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subscriptions, undated.; 238849 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Texas Employment Commission, 1992-1997.; 238848 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Thank-yous ( Ensemble), 1989-1993.; 238847 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Theta Antiques Charity Show, 1993.; 238846 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Trinity episcopal Church, 1994.; 238845 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - TSU; The Piano Llesson, 1995.; 238844 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Venture grant, 1990.; 238843 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Video script, 1993.; 238842 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Volunteer cards, undated.; 238841 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Celeste Walker, Mountaintop Productions correspondence, 1993.; 238840 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Kijana Wiseman correspondence, 1991.; 238839 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Series III: Ensemble Theatre Financial Records, 1983-2008, 238799
  - Ensemble Theatre audit, 1989-1993.; 238837 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ensemble Theatre audit, 1994-1997.; 238836 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble Theatre audit, 1997.; 238835 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bank of America, 1994.; 238834 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Guaranty Federal Bank, 1992, 1993.; 238833 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - South Main Bank, 1991-1994.; 238832 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Unity National Bank, 1991.; 238831 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Building Campaign, 1993.; 238830 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Building fund - National Bank, 1995-1997.; 238829 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Building Fund- Unity National Bank, 1996,1997.; 238828 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ensemble Theatre Bulding account book, 1992-2000.; 238827 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ensemble Theatre cash book, 1993-1995.; 238826 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Ensemble Theatre cash book, 2000.; 238825 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble Theatre check receipts, 1997-2000.; 238824 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Ensemble Theatre contribution tax receipt form, undated.; 238823 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ensemble Theatre financial statements and supporting workpapers, 1 of 2, 1998-2000.; 238822 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ensemble Theatre financial statements and supporting workpapers, 2 of 2, 1998-2000.; 238821 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Ensemble Theatre Gala account book, 1990-1992.; 238820 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Ensemble Theatre Gala account, 1993-2000.; 238819 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ensemble Theatre general account, 1992.; 238818 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble Theatre donation thank-you letters, 1993-1997.; 238817 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ensemble Theatre income and expense projection, 1994-1998undated.; 238816 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Ensemble Theatre general operating budget, 1992-1993.; 238815 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ensemble Theatre Inner Circle correspondence, 1994.; 238814 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Ensemble Theatre IRS correspondence, 1989-1993.; 238813 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ensemble Theatre IRS reinstatement, 1995.; 238812 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Ensemble Theatre c501(c)3 letters, 1983-1993.; 238811 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Ensemble Theatre IRS 990 forms, 1989-1994.; 238810 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Ensemble Theatre IRS Forms 1099, 1992,1993.; 238809 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Ensemble Theatre mail record logbook, 2000- 2001.; 238808 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Ensemble Theatre old fiscal matters, 1991-2000.; 238807 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Ensemble Theatre pledges, 1 of 2, 1993-1996.; 238806 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ensemble Theatre pledges, 2 of 2, 1993-1996.; 238805 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ensemble Theatre contribution tax receipt book, 1994-1995.; 238804 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ensemble Theatre receipts and invoices, 1991-1996.; 238803 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ensemble Theatre record book 1 of 2, 1997-2000.; 238802 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ensemble Theatre record book 2 of 2, 1987-1996.; 238801 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Ensemble Theatre posters, 1992, 2008.; 238800 (Box 15, Folder 1)